[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
[Music]
Tesla hello and welcome to another
episode of the AI native Dev and this is
going to be a bit of a mashup episode
episode where we're going to take a
listen uh to a number of excerts from
previous episodes where we talk about
whether we as organizations are ready to
be able to say this product works better
after these changes to my model uh and
this really uh takes account of various
things including eval testing
evaluations regression testing and so
forth this is going to be a mash up
between Dez trainer intercom founder as
well as rashab hotra who is the head of
AI at source graph uh Tamar yosua who is
the president of products and Technology
at glean and lastly but by no means last
Simon last the notion co-founder and CTO
we're going to start off with Dez
trainers uh take and one of the things I
love about Dres trainer is of course he
recognizes dev's love to ship code and
one of the things that is really
important when we're using llms in our
applications is we don't truly
understand we don't truly know if
something really works until it's in
production using real production data
real data that the users are throwing at
it and one of the lovely quotes that Dez
mentioned in in his section is that with
sufficiently simple tests Dez could be
as smart as Einstein because the tests
are so simple they could both obviously
do so so well at it in this section of
the episode Dez talks about this
wonderful thing called torture test
which is in Dez's words all the
psychotic scenarios that Finn the
intercom tool will get put into in the
real world so it's this set of torture
tests that can really ascertain whether
changes to the model changes to prompts
Etc really do have an effect in
production so over to guy and Des we
have the pleasure dubious pleasure of
building llm based products at tessle
I've had some of that at sneak it's
different they're annoying they are hard
to evaluate whether you're doing your
job correctly or not sometimes costs are
different cicd is different some of the
tools are quite immature and we're
talking probably a year before that
experience that I'm referring to here
how hard was it for a developer who
previously didn't work in that
surrounding to adapt it how did you help
the the dev team not just hey I
reprioritize this feature or am I
overblowing the the change the change is
Big it's actually been a subject of a
lot of internal debate I'll give the
umbrella answer and then we can get to
specifics in a little bit but generally
speaking everything about how we build
software products Chang is when you
bring in generative AI probability based
systems or whatever you want to call it
does classic product development is some
sort of like Double Diamond it's like
research make decisions build like ship
and then see if it works whatever you
have like extra diamonds all over the
place when it's like AI because it's you
don't start with appears the user
problem let's solve it you you tend to
start with what's technically possible
to begin with and then you say hey does
this new technical capability let's say
hey we can read PDFs in a second okay
does that map onto any problems that we
have to solve for our users and then you
find one of those and then so then
you've worked out this thing can be
built and it seems like it solves this
problem even then everyone's DNA and
software is so build it and ship it and
move on to the next fature what's the
big deal and I think the problem is once
these things go live you still don't
know if it works so you have to do so
much whereas in typical boring bread and
butter B2B Sal so I wonder can we merge
expenses okay so you get two receipts
you have to combine them oh okay if you
ship that feature and people use it
you're like great you're not sitting
here going oh I wonder if it works
you're assuming that they like the
mathematics worked or whatever yeah
whereas in all these systems once it
goes live it goes through a whole other
like almost like product Evolution which
is it actually working the way we
thought it did and obviously we do our
best to not just test these systems on
what we call Happy poths a happy poth is
like how do I reset my password
an unhappy path is hey my account is
stored in my husband's name and it's my
credit card and I need to move it to his
credit card but also we need to change
address at the same time that's where
like these systems struggle massively
they're all brilliant at like how do I
reset my password in the same way like
if me and Einstein sit down and take a
maths test and it's just basic
arithmetic I look as a as smart as
Einstein so you have to have this higher
pass filter to get you but nothing like
reality bats last in AI it's still last
person to step up and reality tells you
like hey Finn works great in all these
circumstances but here's a pocket that
it doesn't work in here's an area that
that I can't reach or whatever so I
think the first thing I'd say to the
question of enabling devs and paring
devs to work in this llm first world is
like getting out of your head the idea
that things just simply do or don't work
because it's all a spectrum now getting
out of your head the your core job is to
just clarify or remove ambiguity
ambiguity is all over the place it's and
your job is it's such a there's like an
art and science to like threading all
the needles to finding the useful
Solutions and that's before we've
actually sat down in front of a text
Setter and started banging out code
that's is in working out what problem we
could solve why we think it's solvable
like most of your prototypes in this era
are like written by just prompting my
llm and seeing what it does with certain
prompts and seeing what what it does in
response to certain asks and based if
you can get to a consistent reliable set
of behaviors then you can start to think
about about how would we productize this
what are the API calls and then what's
the UI look like and then how would we
describe it and all that but you have so
much like pre-work to do all that said
there is obviously around any given like
product if we just I'll take F because
it's the one I know best there is still
a lot of bread and butter B2B SAU
you have to build someone has to import
docks and somebody has to have
permissions and it has to be charged for
it so there's a pricing feature like
it's not all it's not like you're an LM
engineer or boost it's the the secondary
features that are fall into the classic
like reporting engine still draws graphs
that that's not
new like any like engine if you build
any sort of proper product at the end of
the day the engine is 10 20% of the
surface of thect exactly that and I
think there's a whole thin wrapper thick
wrapper debate that happens a lot in the
industry and I think like Finn is very
much like a thick rapper there's a lot
around Finn that needs to be there to
make it work really well such that the
actual the pieces are like the the
little like the resolution engine that
sits inside of it that is a part of the
puzzle it's a really important high
impact part but it alone isn't
sufficient it still needs the 16 other
things the vector search the content
importing all that sort of stuff so
sounds like a massive change sounds like
the a lot of the changes is in the sum
the total of the product there's a good
chunk of people that are still working
on things that don't require them to
change their ways of working but still a
good portion that did maybe yeah in the
in the total so I guess are there some
key takeaways like I'm sure you've tried
things and some worked you had a little
bit of a head start because he did have
some AI
capabilities but we had an AI product
live since I think 2017 2018 so like we
definitely had prior experience here and
that was one of the reasons we could
move fast because we were able to reuse
a lot of our existing features for
example like the vector search engine
we' already built one for a previous
product Etc so that's one of the reasons
why we were like out of the gates so
fast if I was to really say like the
biggest lessons I've observed like to be
care what I'm skipping over here is I'm
sure there are libraries and apis and
all sorts of stuff you need to read and
get good at Etc but I think to actually
be a a performance engineer in this era
requires some amount of ability to
interrogate data or perform data science
to measure outcomes to give you a very
simple example when we make a change
like we've run probably like 50
different AB tests on Finn's performance
and it's very tempting everyone comes in
who might Jo join the group and say
something like oh I have a cool feature
I could add how about we make it so that
blah like how about we may consider that
it'll always ask this question at the
end of the thing and what you don't
realize is like all of these things are
different iterations of a resolution
engine whose job is ultimately to give
him a question answered and if you break
that it doesn't matter how cool your
little addition was now the thing is
that's not a binary yes no condition
it's like today Finn's performance is
about 50% of so 50% of inbound support
volume will be resolved by Finn if
somebody rolls at a cool feature that
brings that 50 down to 40 that's a
problem yeah if they do that and don't
even know to check or to realize or to
look at its performance over a trailing
30 days whatever that's an even bigger
problem so it there's a very much you
need to work out you have to understand
trick to working with these systems is
to bottle up a probabilistic outcome and
productize it and you have to work out
who is allowed play with the
probabilities of that and understand
that it's not like two different worlds
it's very easy for somebody in our
messenger team to damage the performance
of Finn even though they don't write to
that code base but if they frame it
wrong and they introduce Finn in the
wrong way it'll change what people write
and if it changes what people right then
it'll change how fin performs so it's
really like the the extra skill required
here is the ability to assess does this
thing do the job it's supposed to do at
a really high performance level and you
have to some way to measure that some
way to test to have bake offs of
different engines against each other
some way to have an acceptance framework
for when all right that's been for 30
days no one's complaining it looks like
we got a 4% increase in resolutions ship
it it's like that none of those skills
really existed before in I'd say in most
companies but definitely not in
intercome yeah no it sounds fascinating
I guess the good news is there's some
analogy between what you're describing
and the state-of-the-art in terms of
continuous deployment right if you're
working with fut Flags if you're in
Facebook and you're shipping I forget
the name of their sort of feature system
there some gradual number of people then
there's some similarity of it but this
is much more and mass much more
predictable and pretty much does it kill
almost substantially the value of a sort
of cicd assessment for anything that
isn't the more bread and butter sasie
how much having run with this now for a
bit how trustworthy or how revealing are
the results of the synthetic tests or
the cicd type the predeployment test
that you have yeah I mean we have two
tests we have one test we perform
internally which is expensive toome
which is like our torture test so let's
just say
it's all the psychotic scenarios that F
will get put into in the real world but
we where we want to make sure it doesn't
like barf so we don't do this unless we
have good reason but let's just say like
GPT 4 Z drops or something like that 40
the tempting thing to do and you'll see
a lot of our competitors do this is just
holy new model plug it in we're
good and I think what that says to me is
it speaks to the maturity of their roll
out like we also know the same API end
points to Ping if you want 40 like it's
not we weren't sitting going well I
wonder how do you do it
it says our approach to such a scenario
is okay let's first of all Ru distri a
torture test and our torture test is
there to deliberately give us hard
situations where we have a very clear
outcome so for example let's say Tesla
was using fin would you want Tesla's
bought to recommend competitors over
tesle would you want it to answer a tier
three question if it did know the answer
how would you want it to behave would
you want it to make up an answer a long
variety like genuinely hundreds of
scenarios where most people agree on
what the right outcome is but like GPT
40 might not agree with that so it's
this is where like you have to control
and contain the behavior so once it
clears the torture test and we look at
its performance then we'll move to look
let's put this live let's see how it
works in actual reality which often
times it's just but in a gradual fashion
like you wouldn't turn it on for
everybody you would graduate you would
yes absolutely that's a great segment
from Dez and one of the things I love at
the end that he said was it's super easy
just to drop in a new model into your
application but you really don't know
what that means for users without that
pre-testing uh and the evaluation
testing how does that new model behave
how is it going to change its answers uh
to the same user question if you change
that model really important to
understand that changing is easy but
it's not the smart thing necessarily to
do without that pretest so thank you
very much to De okay uh next up we have
Risha the head of AI at source graph now
Risha is very passionate about
evaluations because he has a very deep
history in machine learning and one of
the things that he talks about quite a
bit in in his piece here is about how
you can test models with the zero to one
metric and one thing actually really
strong takeaway that he leaves us with
is how writing a good evaluation is
actually more important than training a
good model over to re and testing is
going to be very Sim similar as well
right if someone's writing code in the
in their ID line by line and that's
maybe using a code generation as well
like Cody they're going to likely want
to be able to have test step step in
sync so as I write code you're
automatically generating tests that are
effectively providing me with that
assurance that that the automatically
generated code is working as I want to
yeah that's a great point I think this
is more like errors multiply yeah if I'm
evaluating something after long writing
it then it's worse off right because the
errors I could have stopped the earlier
on and then debugged it and fixed it
locally and then moved on so especially
so taking a step back look I love
evaluation I really in machine learning
I started my PhD thinking that hey
matths and like fancy graphical models
are the way to have impact using machine
learning right and you spend one year in
the industry realize nah it's not about
the fancy model it's about do you have
an evaluation you have these metrics do
you know when something is working
better yeah so I think getting the 0 to
one on evaluation on these data sets
that is really key for any machine
learning problem y now especially when
what do you mean by the 0 to one then
yeah 0 to one is look at like whenever a
new language model gets launched right
people are saying that hey for coding
llm Lama 3 does well on coding why
because oh we have this human eval data
set and a passet one metric let's unpack
that human eval data set is a data set
of 164 questions hey write me a binary
search in this code right so essentially
it's like you get a text and you write a
function and then you're like hey does
this function run correctly so they have
a unit test for that and if it passes
then then you get plus one right yeah so
now this is great it's a great start but
is it really how people are using Cod
and a bunch of other coding tools no
they like if I'm an Enterprise developer
if let's say I'm in a big bank then I
have 20,000 other peers and there are
like 30,000 depositories right I'm not
writing bin research independent of
everything else right I'm working in a
massive code base which has been edited
across the last 10 years and there's
some dependency by some team in Beijing
and there's a function which I haven't
even read right and maybe it's in a
language I don't even care about
understand my point is the evaluation
which we need for these Real World
products is different than the
benchmarks which we have in the industry
right now the 0 to one for evaluation is
that hey sure let's use passet one in
human at the start on day Zero but then
we see that you improve it by 10% we
have results when we actually did
improve pass it one by 10 15% we tried
it online on COD users and the metrics
dropped yeah and we writing a block post
about it at offline online correlation
yeah because if you trust your offline
metric pass it one you improve it you
hope that hey amazing users are going to
love it yeah it wasn't true the context
is so different yeah the context are so
different now this is this means that I
got to develop an evaluation for my
feature and I got my evaluation should
represent how my actual users using this
feature feel about it just because it's
better on a metric which is an industry
Benchmark doesn't mean that improving it
will improve actual user experience and
can that change from user to user as
well so you mention a bank there if five
other Banks is it going to be the same
for them if something not in the finch
going be that's a great point I think
the Nuance you're trying to say is that
hey one are you even feature aware in
your evaluation because passet one is
not featur away right yeah passet one
doesn't care about auto complete or
unitize generation or code fixing I
don't care what the end use case or
application is this is just the
evaluation so I think the first jump is
have an evaluation data set which is
about your feature right the evaluation
data set for unit generation is going to
be different than code completion it's
going to be different than code edits
it's going to be different than chart so
I think the 0 to one we talking about
five minutes
you got to do Z to ones for each of
these features yeah and that's not easy
because evaluation doesn't come
naturally and once you have it then the
question becomes that hey okay once I
have it for my feature then hey can I
reuse it across Industries is it testing
now is it guardrails that become the
most important thing and almost I would
say more important than code or or or is
still code the thing that that we need
to care about the most yeah I think like
if I view this extreme of like again if
I put my evaluation heart right I think
I want to be one of the most most
prominent prop proponents vocal
proponent of evaluation in the industry
not just cod in the machine learning
industry we should do more
evaluation so there I would say that
writing a good evaluation is more
important than writing a good model
important than writing a better context
Source because you don't know what
what's a better context Source if you
don't have a way to evaluate it right so
I think for me evaluation precedes any
feature development yeah if you don't
have a way to evaluate it then you don't
you're just shooting darts in the dark
room right some are going to land by
luck
now there in that world right I have to
ensure that unit test and evaluation is
like ahead in terms of importance and
just like code that said I I think
overall right what's more important is
like task success right which is again
what is Task success you you're not just
looking at unit test as inv valuation
you look at evaluation of the overall
goal which is hey do I do this task
right and then I think if that's where
as an orchestrator if I start treating
these agents could be Cod autoc compete
or like like any specific Standalone
agent powered by Source graph as well
probably so in those words evaluation of
that task because you are the Roman
expert assume AGI exists today assume
the the foundation models are going to
get smarter smarter like billions of
dollars trillions of dollars eventually
into it we train these fan again the
smartest models and they can do
everything but you are best place to
understand your domain on what the goal
is right now right so you are the only
person who can develop that evaluation
of like how do I know that you're
correct how do I know whether you're 90%
correct 92% correct and again right the
marginal gain on 92 to 94 is going to be
a lot more harder than going from to 90
right it always gets like I mean there's
going to be like an exponential hardness
increase over there so essentially the
point then becomes purely on evaluation
purely on unit test right what makes us
what are the nuances of this problem of
this domain which the model needs to get
right and are you are we able to
articulate those and I'll be able to
generate those unit tests or generate
those guard RS and evaluations so that I
can judge how the models are getting
better on that topic right so the models
are going to be far intelligent great
but then what is success you as a domain
expert get to Define that and this is a
great thing not just about coding but
also like any domain expert using
machine learning or these tools across
domains you know what you're using it
for right the other AI tools are just
tools to help you do that job so you
it's I think the onus is on you to write
good evaluation or I mean maybe tomorrow
llm as a judge and like people are
developing Foundation models just for
evaluation right so there going to be
other tools to help you do that as well
code Foundation models for like unites
maybe that's the thing in six months
from now right the point then becomes
what should it focus on that that's the
role you're playing orchestrating but
like orchestrating on the evaluation oh
did you get that corner piece right oh
you know what this is a criticality of
the system right again right the payment
Gateway link and the authentication link
some of these get screwed up then
massive bad things happen right so you
know that so I think that's where like
the human in the loop and your input to
the system starts getting cross great
stuff from mhab uh next up we're going
to be hearing from Tamar yosa who is the
president of products and Technology at
glean and gle's a really interesting
company effectively does Enterprise
search across a vast number of sources
many of which have very sensitive data
including HR systems and various things
within that Enterprise so glean as a
product allow multiple models to be used
and the user can select which one they
choose to use glean interestingly
obviously don't have access directly
into that data because that data is very
sensitive to the customer so when it
comes to thinking about how glean would
test and and run evaluations across
multiple models with data that they
don't have access to it becomes a bit of
a challenge and makes evaluation testing
very hard now one of the really
interesting things that was talked about
in this episode was how glean use llms
as a judge and as a jury and it's a
really interesting concept of not
necessarily having employees from glean
uh look at the prompts and the queries
that are being created uh and try to
validate them but it's actually about
having an LL
do that validation so the llm is
determining whether those queries are
correct and of course that determinism
is very hard as well to having that jury
perhaps lessens that non-determinism
effect of an L um so this is really
another great episode and so over to guy
tomorrow so I guess let's talk indeed
keep promising talking about the sausage
making let's do that now I guess what is
it like building a product that works
this way the the the results of the
product vary by the data that comes in
the success rates are very different and
that's on top of the fact that the llms
move at such a kind of lightning pace
and so you get new models all the time
and if I understand correctly you
actually even don't pick the model you
have to work with models that the
customer does so maybe tell us a little
bit about how do you interact with the
model so just said that but what I'm
really interested is you talked about km
as a judge you had a post about this
just how do you know that your product
works it's very difficult so it's the
non-deterministic aspect is the most
interesting and challenging my first
week at glean I was talking to the head
of the assistant quality team just to
learn what do you do and how does it
work and realize that a lot of their
time was spent talking to customers who
did not have the right expectations of
what the what it could do or were
complaining that it was
non-deterministic I did this query once
I did it again and it didn't get the
same thing and we're starting to get
used to ch GPT and this the concept of
non-deterministic but in an Enterprise
you're a CIO you buy software you pay a
lot of money for it you expect it to
have the same answer every time and so
one is getting our customers comfortable
with what llms can do and what the
boundary conditions are is part of what
we have to do in our product and it
can't just be in the marketing and in
the enablement you have to have some way
in the product to take care of this as
well to understand what are the
challenges going to be for people so I
explained the rag architecture so we
have our way of evaluating the search
which most of the team came from Google
search ranking built eval tools just
like Google search head so that kind of
that's like bread and butter like how do
you eval search we have a whole process
for Ev this is not the user side this is
internal this is
toate whether you're search is working
correctly with information the the
engineers see your engineers this is our
ranking the ranking algorithms with a
lot of information on exactly what was
triggered and what wasn't and what
scores it had now it is a little bit
more difficult because it Google you
could use thirdparty Raiders to say
here's a change we're making is this
change good or bad evaluate it but
because this is Enterprise data we can't
use third party Raiders we can only use
our tools and Engineers to look at the
data so that's a another wrinkle on top
for for Enterprise but but going back to
your question of what's different is
under understanding the user mindset
when they're using this product how do
you help them through that to give them
guard rails so they can better
understand what the product can do and
then how do you evaluate it and how do
you make sure that it's working as
intended with this new technology that
nobody fully understands why it's giving
the answer that it does yeah what are
some examples of things that you would
do in the product to to help to help
people understand so a big one is
suggest one of the things about glean is
that we understand your organization so
in the uh connectors that we do we also
have a workday connector active
directory so we understand who you are
who's who are your peers who's on your
team so we can suggest prompts that
people in your team has been have been
using oh you're a PM here's a prompt
from another PM that things that they've
been doing that you might want to try
and so we can suggest or generic
suggestions we've been experimenting
with all different ones but that can
help guide people into areas of this is
the right this is ways that you can get
value and that's going to be really
important and we want to do a lot more
of that and the clean apps was a big way
of doing that as well here's some more
structured prompts and triggers this is
where if you have an it question you'll
go here if you have a want to build a
customer brief here's a clean app for
building a customer brief so that helps
people go to things that somebody has
curated somebody like the 5% people in
the company who really understand how to
work with prompts and llms they're going
to do that and they're going to help and
we're going to be doing more and more of
that and I hope that is a way that's a
whole another angle of how we are doing
that and then we also have just teams
dedicated to eval and understanding what
changes need to be made what don't how
to evaluate new models um as you
mentioned we customers can decide what
model they want to use we validate the
model we certify it I should say if a
Gemini 1.5 Pro comes out so we will
certify it for our customers before we
enable them to use it but we have let
our customers pick open AI anthropic or
Gemini for the llm aspect of the work
and so that's another thing that's
tricky also is working with the
different models but how so I I
understand in like the suggest notion or
the idea of disseminating actually
probably a useful practice for any
product not an llm specific one which is
take the forerunners and provide an easy
way to disseminate the their sample uses
to the rest of the organization but on
the other side in terms of what happens
if it fails what happens ifin naations
are a thing in this world so ranges from
it didn't okay maybe you're good on the
search side so it finds the relevant
data you feel pretty good but did it
understand it did it process it
correctly did it present it correctly
how do you evaluate it when you certify
what types of tools are at your disposal
to know when you're using a new model or
even just evolving your software that it
got better in so first of all in the
product customers can do a thumbs up
thumbs down obviously we get more thumbs
down than thumbs up because that's just
the nature of people but we but that's
helpful until all those queries go come
back to us so that we know here's a set
of of bad queries we also evaluate
things like can search it's easy did
somebody click on it did they find what
they were looking for in the assistant
it's trickier because they might have
gotten the answer or not gotten the
answer but for example if they try a
couple queries in an assistant and go to
search afterwards and then find the
document that they needed we know that
the assistant didn't give the answer so
we have some we have a metric the index
the satisfaction index from searching
the assistant so we look at that and we
measure that very heavily of how many
bad queries did we get how many thumbs
down did we get so that's one yeah and
that's post those are all things that
people using the product right that's
the proxy for how well are we doing and
if we're doing hill climbing to improve
is it going up or going down and then
evaluating is super tricky so we have as
you mentioned we've started using llm as
a judge and there are many ways that
that the llm could go wrong or the whole
assistant could go wrong it could pick
the wrong query to send to the retrieval
engine theet retrieval could not find
the document it could find the wrong one
or it could miss some something and then
in the generative not a complete answer
it could not be grounded in the facts it
might pull in public data instead of the
data that you had and then so you've got
the completeness the groundedness and
the factualness so we've been using llms
to judge our answers for the assistant
in these different areas so completeness
is one that we get the most thumbs down
if it's not a complete answer we'll get
thumbs down for it and then we've
correlated the thumbs down with l as a
judge and the completeness so that's the
most easiest for an llm to then evaluate
the results of the llm yeah and so we
have completeness we have grounded did
it tell you which which context it came
from and then the factualness is the
hardest and the factualness what you
need is a golden set essentially
factualness being the you did not
hallucinate grounded is more of the
hallucinations we don't have a big
problem with hallucinations at glean
because of the rag based architecture
and because we do the citation
so the groundedness is the most aligned
to to hallucinations but sometimes it's
not grounded in Enterprise doc because
it might be like the stock price that
you ask for for a company and it might
just be public knowledge the factfulness
is was it LMS are very confident so
they'll say with great confidence that
something is correct and then a user
will not thumbs down those because
they'll just assume it's correct those
are the most dangerous right and that
what we're doing is trying to actually
have a golden set where having an llm
extract queries from documents and then
measure the effectiveness of Are We
finding them so we F get the golden set
and then we're so this one actually
we're still working on the fact how to
best measure it but the best part that
we've done now is now we have a
repeatable process for llm is Judge we
have an evil framework of how we use and
we should just turn the crank when a new
model comes out and we can get an
evaluation across these metrics for new
models and for changes as we're making
changes in the code we can evaluate them
more easily is it perfect no but it's a
lot better than Engineers manually going
and looking at every query at the
results and that golden set needs to be
created per
customer so we use a lot of times we use
our data for some of these golden sets
to make sure but we do have in our eval
we actually run queries in our customer
environment in their deployments because
we can't look at their content but we
can run things and evaluate them and get
the results of the evaluation so that's
interesting and that's a good learning
so in you can't look at their data you
have to make sure that your check did
not cause problems with their data or
see at least try to assess that's the
case so what you're agreeing with them
is that you'd be able to run some
processes that are not actually
functional like run a bunch of these
tests on their platform with their data
but you won't access the data you just
get the results of like thumbs up thumbs
down different version of the thumbs up
thumbs down to say yeah feels good for
you to to deploy this this new version
or to upgrade to this new model Etc
we're very cautious of making sure we
have very strict agreements of how we're
handling customer data but we absolutely
run regressions and which was a it's a
interesting process that we've gone
through yeah and so we're talking about
llm as a judge which is the the llm
looks at the answer and says the result
I see in the golden set seems
sufficiently familiar sufficiently
similar to the result the product the
live product gave right now and then you
I found interesting in the blog post
that you you wrote about this there's
this notion of llm jurry which I know
has has the risk of taking the analogy a
bit too far but I guess is that do you
want to say a couple words about that uh
it's exactly what it sounds like just
multiple you want to assess not just one
voice but multiple voices to make sure
that you're aligning and I guess partly
a means to deal with the fact that llm
themselves like the evaluator itself is
a random or is a non-deterministic
entity so oddly actually quite aligned
to the reason there is a judge and jury
in the actual human judicial system and
last up we have Simon L notion
co-founder and CTO now notion AI is of
course one of the most impressive
running real world applications of AI
and in the Snippets that we're going to
be sharing with you today one of the
interesting things here is about how
Simon details how notion effectively log
uh failures that are occurring with
exact reproduction capabilities and what
this allows them to do is effectively
build up a data set of failures with
regressions now there's an iterative
improvement Loop here whereby one can
collect the failures adjust prompts
rerun the evaluations and then validate
the fixes against those evaluations so
it's a really interesting Loop of how
there's a continuous Improvement uh with
validation from The evals as well uh and
of course one really important thing is
there needs to be an optin from a
privacy point of view there needs to be
that optin for data sharing uh for
evaluation purposes only that allow and
ensure rather that privacy and
segregation uh from test to production
uh data so uh here's Simon co-founder of
notion and CT yeah I'm very curious to
dive in because indeed some things are
the same and you just want to tap into
them and some things are are quite
substantially different but I guess
still on the organization do you think
about the team that is originally
building it as a platform team how did
you consider that division now that
you've been building this for a couple
of years and you have it sounds like
multiple teams working it how do you
think about the shared infrastructure if
you will between those or the shared
learnings or evaluation methods as we'll
touch on in a sec how do you think about
I guess enabling these other teams to
adopt thei more easily yeah that's good
question yeah initially we didn't think
of it that way as more just like a end
to- end product team the only goal is
just to just ship them yeah just to ship
useful stuff and then we're learning
along the way how to do evals and then
our goal is to make it more of a
platform team so we're trying to take
what we build and expose it as something
reproducible I would say it's actually
pretty tricky because in many ways we
don't really do any training of models
it's all about taking the best models
out there and packaging them into the
product and making everything work well
which involves doing logging in the
right way like setting up your prompt
doing logging in the right way doing
eals all stuff and it's interesting most
of it is actually there's not that much
technically challenging I would say
about the platform aspect a lot of it is
more about the best practice of how you
do it and the knowledge of what steps
you take and even how to think about it
yeah it's a tricky thing to get other
people to work on without context what
we've had most success with actually is
when someone new wants to work on AI
we've had a lot of success with just
having them join the AI team temporarily
and then they just join our standups and
get in the weeds with us every day and
then quickly pick up all the context
around like how to do EVS how to iterate
on prompts and yeah we found it
challenging the other way where we just
like give the like the code pointers to
all the different layers of the stack
here's the thing that would run the
inference or whatever it is but yeah and
the code isn't that complicated I would
say the complexity is actually more in
like the best practice of how you you do
things and the mental model I don't even
think about it yeah yeah I think that
makes perfect sense I actually had
Patrick deis who was a b kind of devops
luminary on the podcast and we talked
about how the analogies work from the
devops era and a lot of it is indeed
about platform teams and reuse but also
about embedding and about someone's
walking a mile in your shoes a little
bit and learning both for empathy as you
might get annoyed later on when the
product doesn't work quite as you want
but for skill sharing and insecurity in
devops we use the same approach I think
we're running out of letters we can add
into the devops kind of combo I think we
need to find a new strategy there but I
think the approaches themselves are work
quite well I love that approach and it
makes perfect sense to me maybe let's
indeed I want to talk a bit more about
the skills and those gaps but maybe
let's first describe these what has been
repeated often times and and this
probably sent most distinctly by Dez at
intercom in an early episode here is
that it's really hard to Mill whether
your product works when you're building
on AI so I guess what has your
experience been when you're building
these capabilities how do you think
about evaluation about testing about
knowing whether it hit a threshold but
also knowing whether it hasn't regressed
yeah it's super hard it's a really
different experience than the prei world
most of my experien is in building
notion building products and it's been
honestly really painful it's very
exciting and fun and like I'm pretty
obsessed with the new technology but
it's very painful and I hav missed the
old world in the old world I could have
an idea and it might take me longer than
I thought but I could definitely ship it
but in the AI world I can often have an
idea and and then be surprised that that
didn't work in some some way I didn't
expect I would say I guess the way I
think about it is it's a twofold
challenge of one is for the situations
that you test you need to make sure that
those work and they don't regress and
then there's this nebulous space of
things that you haven't even tested it
and it can be arbitrary and then filling
enough of that space so that you're
confident that it's going to match the
distribution of what uses are going to
request enough that you're reasonably
competent you can never like like like
fully match it yeah I guess the way I
think about that is yeah you need like a
repeatable system or engine around this
and the key pieces are something like
you need you need to set up good logging
such that interactions can be called up
again if it fails in some way you can go
look at that and it's extremely
important to be able to exactly
reproduce the the failure situation the
log has to be an exact reproduction of
the error and then you should be able to
just rerun that inference with the exact
same input right that's really important
if you can't do that you're totally SC
and that creates probably some
challenges like I fully relate to the
full logging even more so than in
regular instrumented systems how do you
work around the kind of the privacy
concerns or some of the user data
concerns around it yeah so so we take
that really seriously what we do is we
have an opt-in early Access program so
when you use no scenario we show you
this little little popup and the default
is no you can opt in to to shareing data
with us and we don't use it for training
it's just for evaluation so basically
that allows us to see the logs like if
you thumbs down we can actually see the
log with the input and then we can add
it to an eval data set and we segregate
out the prod data to make sure that it's
not contaminated with other sources but
yeah that's been extremely helpful let
people opt in and our user base is large
enough that even if a pretty small
percentage opt in it's still quite a lot
of data so logging is one yeah so
logging is one so yeah I would say the
next step is around collecting the
failures into data sets that's pretty
important so just like organizing them
in some reasonable way such that that
for the given task you have some data
set or data sets that are like these are
all the cases that we care about and all
the known previous failures and then the
next bit is being able to evaluate that
a given failure is still happening or
not and that can be really hard there's
many ways to do evals I think about you
can have deterministic or non-
deterministic evals definitely best use
deterministic when you can and then you
can use like a model gr eval when not
for model gr they work best when it's as
concrete and specific as possible I've
seen people fail a lot doing mod gr Dev
vals when it's like too generic or the
task is too difficult I think I said
this in the last one but if your mod
grade eval is not like robustly easy for
the model then you have to have an eval
for your eval and you just created like
a new stack of problems an infinite Loop
so it relates to the the data piece so
the data sounded like going further back
you have to create a set of test cases
for the things you want to work and then
a set of cases for problematic ones I
guess that's synthetic that's at the
beginning was you build a feature and
then you need to have access to real
world scenarios and you curate out of
that data set of failure cases with the
proper user permission like amidst the
users that opted in to help improve the
system I guess do you accumulate over
there good cases as well does the data
set mostly grow in the negative sense of
don't do this or is it the same one is
it basically because you're like here's
a scenario here's the correct and here's
the incorrect answer I tend not to care
about good cases that much I think the
the main focus is because what's the
actionable value of that maybe it's nice
to have a few of them just as a sanity
check but but to me the main goal is to
collect concrete regressions and then
fix them and then make sure that they
stay fixed and then over time you're
ratcheting up all these things that they
used to not work are now working and
then you're growing this data set of
things that continue to work and that's
ideal you'll often find issues that you
just can't really fix and so that's that
that's yeah we'll come back to that
that's really interesting because my
product works at this percent percentage
of yeah the models have limits there's
many issues that we can fix and we're
not a foundation model company it's like
all right we'll just wait till the next
model comes out hopefully it'll fix this
one so you want some kind of eval it
could be just like a like a human grad
eval although that can that'll quickly
get out of control then the really key
next thing is you need to enter this
Loop where you find some new regression
you addit to your data set then you
change the prompt in some way then you
rerun the examples in the data set and
then you need to be able to decide
whether it's like better or worse and
ideally that's a as automated as
possible and then ship that change and
then this just this constant Loop of new
example improve the prompt Ro the
product and I think on the evil side
notion is pretty open or flexible in
what you can do with it there are a lot
of degrees of freedom of it it's easy to
think about non-deterministic
evaluations that you can have no you're
looking at text and unstructured data
and the likes what's an example of a
structured evaluation that you can do in
an ocean AI capability yeah a lot of
them like anything to do with formatting
the output in some way maybe it's XML
maybe it's Json that's ideal I think
about if you're having some issue the
best way to solve it is by solving it
with a validator make it so that the
invalid output is Impossible by
structuring the output in some way where
you can deterministically say that the
bad output is incorrect that's like the
best way to solve any problem and it's
easiest way to to evaluate it another
determinist that we use all the time is
I love using Min classifiers as as part
of the flow classifiers are really great
I by classifier I just mean some
inference that outputs like an enum like
like set of possible values classifiers
are really great because they're really
easy to eval you classify the result of
the the product's activity like you
classify the output from the llm no
actually as part of the flow so for
example one thing we need to do as part
of the the chat experience is decide
whether to search or not just as an
example so it's should I search should I
not search like yes or no basically
these other classifiers that are more
two possible values but yeah those are
really great in large part because
they're so easy to evaluate because you
just have this gr truth output and then
you just compare the actual versus
expected it's really great for that
reason you can collect a big data set
and you can get a score yeah and I guess
what has been the driver behind the
choice not to fine tune or actually you
know what I I I might be jumping to
conclusions here you said you're not
training Foundation models of it do you
find yourself fine-tuning the model yeah
so we've tried fine-tuning extensively
I personally bang my head on it a lot I
think I need to ask open AI but I feel
like I'm if not the highest maybe like
99th percentile like number of fine
tunes created yeah we try fine tuning
quite a lot I would say yeah the big
issue with fine
tuning is that you're making your job
like a 100 times harder at least because
I need to collect this whole data set
the actual fine tuning process can be
difficult especially if using L slower
you have to wait for things to train and
then it's really hard to debug issues
you're basically like creating this
black box where any of your new examples
as you do the success toine tuning runs
any new examples can poison the entire
data set you can mess up the model so it
really requires you to have extremely
good evaluations and it's really hard to
debug issues so I've had issues with
fine tuning where you know I I literally
would spend weeks trying to figure out
what the problem was and just extremely
hard yeah I would say I'm honestly not
that bullish on companies outside of the
foundation model companies doing fine
tuning and if I like meet a startup and
they say they're doing fine tuning I I
actually now think of that as like a
negative update a lack of experience you
buy into the promise but it doesn't
actually yeah itself in the real world
and I got bit by this this bug too like
it sounds so cool and like I think as
Engineers we want to have more control
we want to do a technically cool thing
um you know the technically like
powerful thing and I was totally
susceptible that and and it was really
fun to do it uh but I don't know I'm a
huge fan of in context learning like
it's gonna get better yeah there's a lot
of reasons to do it another big reason
not to fine tune is if you're not a
foundation model company you really want
to just be using the best model at any
given time and the progress is so fast
and so if someone doesn't work now
there's a good chance it's going to work
in the near future and if you're
fine-tuning you're really just locking
yourself in to this slow complicated
process that makes it hard to update and
context learning is amazing because if
it's a new model I can switch the next
day and I guess in in that case my next
question is like how often do you try
different models and how rigorous a
testing process do you feel is necessary
to make that switch because those are
probably new features are new features
you control the timeline a new model
comes along I guess you still control
the timeline of how quickly you you roll
it out how do you think about the
trade-off between onean thing to tap
into the new hotness versus I know
potentially slow or how confident do you
feel about hey like the next one came
out can I sort of slot that in and get
it out within the Wii yeah that's a good
question I would say the speed at which
you can do it is really dependent on the
quality of your evals how good do your
evals like how good are they at telling
you confidently that this change will
improve the the overall experience yeah
I would say that's one of the reasons
why evals are so important probably
changing prompts is more important than
changing models that's going to happen
much much more often U but the same
evals work for both right um but yeah we
try to yeah we've definitely invested a
lot in really making sure the tools are
right and and theels are are really good
but also I would say as a Products
Company I I think it's pretty important
not to be just like jerked around
constantly by new models coming out I
think it's important to like think about
like really understanding the task that
you uniquely really care about for
product and your Alpha should be really
deeply understanding the task and what
it means to produce a good result and
the product experience around that and
like watching new capabilities and
releasing them as they come out I think
it's really about you and your product
and like thinking about the models as
like a means to an end to to enable that
and very often a new model like just
it's like shiny and cool but like maybe
it just doesn't really get you much
benefit Tas that you care about yeah I'm
curious now what's your favorite EV
example is it just that specific Cod
base it's an app yeah so it's a it's a
pretty simple app but it touches all the
pieces that that I think are interesting
so it's a calorie tracking app all it is
is it's a table of where it's the food
and the amount of calories and then
there's an input and you can just type
whatever you want and then it's supposed
to extract out each food item and and
the cars add to the table so it involves
a database a back end a front end and
then it also has to write a prompt and
and and call into a language model to do
the extraction and last time I tried it
actually did get the initial version and
then I asked for just one small feature
change and then didn't work from there
they've made huge improvements and it's
like super impressive but yeah I I feel
like we're not quite there yet still and
a massive thank you to Simon there and
of course Tamar rishab and Dez at the
very start of the episode and of course
my co-host Geo for helping host many of
those sessions this has been a very
interesting episode for me personally
just because it's been really nice going
through some of the past episodes and
also picking out some of those learnings
that are consistent and Common from many
leaders who have kindly given the time
to share their thoughts and learnings
with us yeah let us know what you think
if there's other topics that you feel
are are common across episodes let us
know we'll create some further mashups
of them till then thanks very much for
listening again and tune in to the next
[Music]
episode thanks for tuning in join us
next time on the AI native Dev brought
to you by Tesla